{
    "questions": [
      {
        "question": "The literacy rate of Assam according to 2011 census is",
        "options": [
          "A. 72.19 %",
          "B. 72.58 %",
          "C. 73.12 %",
          "D. 73.98 %"
        ],
        "answer": "A. 72.19 %"
      },
      {
        "question": "When the uprising of Patharughat took place",
        "options": [
          "A. 1857",
          "B. 1864",
          "C. 1889",
          "D. 1894"
        ],
        "answer": "D. 1894"
      },
      {
        "question": "Who was the President of the Swaraj Party in Assam during freedom movement",
        "options": [
          "A. Bishnuram Medhi",
          "B. Gopinath Bordoloi",
          "C. Tarun Ram Phookan",
          "D. Maniram Dewan"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Tarun Ram Phookan"
      },
      {
        "question": "The terracotta industry is located in",
        "options": [
          "A. Dhubri",
          "B. Karimganj",
          "C. Goalpara",
          "D. Dhemaji"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Dhubri"
      },
      {
        "question": "The Ahom Kingdom was established in the year",
        "options": [
          "A. 1216",
          "B. 1228",
          "C. 1256",
          "D. 1272"
        ],
        "answer": "B. 1228"
      },
      {
        "question": "The Shiv dol was constructed during the reign of",
        "options": [
          "A. Pramatta Singha",
          "B. Rudra Singha",
          "C. Purandar Singha",
          "D. Siba Singha"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Siba Singha"
      },
      {
        "question": "The Asssam Public Service Commission (APSC) Regulation was promulgated in exercise of the powers",
        "options": [
          "A. 1947",
          "B. 1950",
          "C. 1951",
          "D. 1960"
        ],
        "answer": "C. 1951"
      },
      {
        "question": "The first stadium of Assam was built in",
        "options": [
          "A. Jorhat",
          "B. Golaghat",
          "C. Sibsagar",
          "D. Dhemaji"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Jorhat"
      },
      {
        "question": "Sadiya Khowa Gohain was a",
        "options": [
          "A. Jamindar",
          "B. King",
          "C. Frontier Officer",
          "D. Naval Commander"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Naval Commander"
      },
      {
        "question": "Prachya Sasanavali was edited by",
        "options": [
          "A. Dr. Maheswar Neog",
          "B. Dr. Birinchi Kumar Barua",
          "C. Dr. surya Kumar Bhuyan",
          "D. Alexander Mackenzie"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Dr. Maheswar Neog"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which king is also known by the nicknamed as Bhagaraja",
        "options": [
          "A. Sutiyampha",
          "B. Sutamla",
          "C. Surampha",
          "D. Sunyatpha"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Surampha"
      },
      {
        "question": "During freedom struggle, the \"Mrityu Bahini\" was formed by",
        "options": [
          "A. Chandraprabha Saikiani",
          "B. Pushpalata Das",
          "C. Rani Gaidinlieu",
          "D. Kanaklata Barua"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Pushpalata Das"
      },
      {
        "question": "\"Rang Ghar\" was constructed during the reign of",
        "options": [
          "A. Rudra Singha",
          "B. Rajeswar Singha",
          "C. Pramatta Singha",
          "D. Siv Singha"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Pramatta Singha"
      },
      {
        "question": "When was Assam Provincial Congress Committee formed",
        "options": [
          "A. 1920",
          "B. 1921",
          "C. 1922",
          "D. 1923"
        ],
        "answer": "B. 1921"
      },
      {
        "question": "The author of \"Asomiya Sahityar Buranji\" is",
        "options": [
          "A. Nathan Brown",
          "B. Jatindranath Duara",
          "C. Devendranath Bezbarua",
          "D. Gunabhiram Barua"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Devendranath Bezbarua"
      }
    ]
  }
  